export const ANIMALHUSBANDRYA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The true stomach of ruminants is called",
A: "abomasum",
B: "omasum",
C: "reticulum",
D: "rumen",
answer: "A. abomasum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In animal production, disease-causing organisms are generally called.",
A: "parasites",
B: "pathogens",
C: "pests",
D: "vectors",
answer: "B. pathogens",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The introduction of semen into the reproductive tract of female farm animals without copulation is called.",
A: "pasture mating",
B: "natural insemination",
C: "hand mating",
D: "artificial insemination",
answer: "D. artificial insemination",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following plants is a pasture legume?",
A: "Panicum maximum",
B: "Andropogen gayanus",
C: "Pueraria phaseoloides",
D: "Axonopus compressus",
answer: "C. Pueraria phaseoloides",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Pastures could be improved through",
A: "reseeding and overgrazing",
B: "Fertilizer application and irrigation",
C: "rotational grazing and uncontrolled burning",
D: "padlocking and overgrazing",
answer: "B. Fertilizer application and irrigation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. which of the following types of meat is obtained from sheep?",
A: "beef",
B: "chevon",
C: "mutton",
D: "ham",
answer: "C. mutton",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Rinderpest in cattle is caused by a",
A: "bacterium",
B: "fungus",
C: "protozoan",
D: "virus",
answer: "D. virus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. One of the symptoms of brucellosis in ewes is",
A: "abortion",
B: "convulsion",
C: "depression",
D: "in-coordination",
answer: "A. abortion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A boiler consumed 6.0kg of feed and gained 2.0kg weight in six weeks. Determine the feed: gain ratio",
A: "1:3",
B: "1:4",
C: "3:1",
D: "4:1",
answer: "C. 3:1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following structures is part of the intestine of rabbits?",
A: "Caecum",
B: "Gullet",
C: "Ileum",
D: "Rectum",
answer: "A. Caecum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Forages harvested before flowering and conserved are characterized by",
A: "high fibre",
B: "high protein",
C: "low energy",
D: "low vitamins",
answer: "B. high protein",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The part labelled III is called",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. (No information provided)",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Fertilization occurs in the part labelled",
A: "II",
B: "III",
C: "IV",
D: "V",
answer: "D. IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the labelled parts produces hormones?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "A. I",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following effects is associated with high temperature brooding of chicks",
A: "Low feed consumption",
B: "Low mortality",
C: "Increased growth rate",
D: "Increased profitability",
answer: "A. Low feed consumption",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. If 25kg feed was consumed by 10,000 birds in six hours, determine the quantity of feed required by the same number of birds in one week?",
A: "20kg",
B: "67kg",
C: "400kg",
D: "700kg",
answer: "D. 700kg",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. One of the main reasons for providing light for broilers during production is to",
A: "reduce predators",
B: "increase feed intake",
C: "reduce mortality",
D: "increase exercise",
answer: "B. increase feed intake",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following birds is purposely raised for meat?",
A: "Broilers",
B: "Cockerels",
C: "Layers",
D: "Pullets",
answer: "A. Broilers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. pasture crops are best used in preparing silage when they",
A: "have produced seeds",
B: "are lignified",
C: "are yet to produce flowers",
D: "are producing flowers",
answer: "C. are yet to produce flowers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following management systems of poultry production is least expensive?",
A: "Deep litter",
B: "Battery cage",
C: "Fold units",
D: "Free-range",
answer: "D. Free-range",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A limitation to the effective use of artificial insemination in animal improvement is",
A: "use of semen of exotic breeds",
B: "inability to detect heat in female animals",
C: "availability of facilities to store semen for later use",
D: "when inbreeding effect is not expressed",
answer: "B. inability to detect heat in female animals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following farm animals is most prolific?",
A: "Cattle",
B: "Goat",
C: "Pig",
D: "Sheep",
answer: "C. Pig",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A castrated male sheep is called a",
A: "bullock",
B: "capon",
C: "hog",
D: "wether",
answer: "D. wether",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The part of the tapeworm illustrated is",
A: "embryo",
B: "proglottis",
C: "rostellum",
D: "scolex",
answer: "B. proglottis",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The part labelled III is the",
A: "hook",
B: "genital pore",
C: "mouth",
D: "sucker",
answer: "B. genital pore",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the labelled parts is used by the tapeworm to attach itself to the host?",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "A. I only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In farm animals, hormones are released into the",
A: "bloodstream",
B: "muscle tissue",
C: "adipose",
D: "nervous system",
answer: "A. bloodstream",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following characteristics describes the external features of sheep?",
A: "Convex face",
B: "Concave face",
C: "Erect ear",
D: "Short tail",
answer: "A. Convex face",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. In poultry, nutrients are absorbed mainly in the",
A: "caecum",
B: "proventriculus",
C: "large intestine",
D: "small intestine",
answer: "D. small intestine",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A disadvantage of prolonged inbreeding in farm animals it that it leads to",
A: "reduced vigour among offspring",
B: "increased vigour among offspring",
C: "production of pure breeds",
D: "production of animals with uniform characteristics",
answer: "A. reduced vigour among offspring",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following factors affects the productivity of pasture? I Soil fertility II. Climate III. Weeds",
A: "I and II",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. If the oestrus cycle of a goat is 27 days, how many times will it come on heat in a year?",
A: "14 times",
B: "28 times",
C: "30 times",
D: "60 times",
answer: "B. 28 times",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following statements about ovulation in rabbits is correct?",
A: "Eggs are released every 21 days",
B: "Eggs are released every 26 days",
C: "Eggs are released in the absence of a buck",
D: "Eggs are released in the presence of a buck",
answer: "D. Eggs are released in the presence of a buck",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The endoparasite that creates sores in the liver and lungs of farm animals as it bores through them is",
A: "hookworm",
B: "pinworm",
C: "roundworm",
D: "tapeworm",
answer: "C. roundworm",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following farm animals is a monogastric?",
A: "Bullock",
B: "Boar",
C: "Heifer",
D: "Wether",
answer: "B. Boar",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the labelled part is used to determine a good layer?",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "II and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The part labelled III is the",
A: "nostril",
B: "shank",
C: "comb",
D: "wattle",
answer: "C. comb",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The fundamental principles underlying animal breeding is based on",
A: "genetics",
B: "management",
C: "physiology",
D: "selection",
answer: "A. genetics",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following disease would directly affect milk production in cows",
A: "Mastitis",
B: "Rinderpest",
C: "Trypanosomiasis",
D: "Tuberculosis",
answer: "A. Mastitis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Farm animals producing milk, egg and wool would require",
A: "maintenance ration",
B: "balance ration",
C: "weaning ration",
D: "production ration",
answer: "D. production ration",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]